GILLIAN YEOMANS

Full-Stack Developer

Portfolio: gillian.tech

Github: yeo-yeo

LinkedIn: gyeomans

Email: hello@gillian.tech

I am a former Risk Analyst, retrained as a Full-Stack Developer. I love learning new skills and technologies, and putting them to practical use with my business experience. I am based across London and Rome and enjoy yoga and crosswords.

EXPERIENCE

Founders and Coders, London

18 week full-stack selective bootcamp with a focus on strong fundamentals (e.g. vanilla JS) and project work. Emphasis on pair programming and team mentality. TDD, agile and continuous integration tools used throughout.

The course culminates with a 3-week project for an external product owner: see details overleaf.

British Institute & My English School, Rome

English teacher working with individuals and groups of all ages and all levels: beginners, conversation, business, secondary school exams.

Nephila Advisors, London/Bermuda

Risk Analyst specialising in Nephila's Lloyd's insurance syndicate 2357, in team of 5 overseeing \$330m of GWP. My roles included financial modelling of natural catastrophe impact, operational liaison, underwriting analysis. I developed a number of processes and tools which are still in use 3 years after my departure.

Lloyd's of London

Graduate Programme in Lloyd's insurance market: rotations in Research, Market Analysis and external placement to Nephila syndicate 2357 in Bermuda.

STACK

2019-2020 **FE/BE**

HTML
CSS
JavaScript
React
Node.js
Express
PostgreSQL
Airtable
Google Maps

2017-2019

Jest Tape NYC Codecov

TESTING

2015-2017

2013-2015

TOOLS
Git
Travis
Heroku
Netlify
AWS (CCP)

DESIGN

Figma Adobe XD

PROJECTS

Chatti

DevOps Lead / Developer

HTML, CSS, React, Javascript, Express, PostgreSQL

- An app which provides parents with activities targeting early stages development goals
- DevOps responsibilities included: setting up the project architecture (React components structure, server, database) and continuous integration tools (Travis, Codecov)
- I was also active in organising the team's workflow (sprint planning, prioritising, reviewing Kanban board) and communication with the product owner
- My favourite parts of the project were:
 - implementing authentication (hashing passwords, creating/verifying JWTs, setting cookies)
 - 'connecting the dots' between the many different moving parts (React props/state management, fetch calls, database queries, rendering data)

www.chatti-app.herokuapp.com https://github.com/fac18/chatti

Signpost

QA Lead / Developer

HTML, CSS, React, Javascript, Express, Airtable

- A directory app which lists services for people at risk of homelessness
- One week design sprint and user testing using Figma and rapid prototyping, two oneweek development sprints
- As well as general development, I was responsible for implementing testing and maintaining a good quality of overall code
- I took the lead on implementing the Google Maps and Geocoding APIs, involving careful study of documentation and some lateral thinking to implement and customise in React

www.signpost-app.herokuapp.com https://github.com/fac18/signpost

VOLUNTEERING

Code Your Future, Rome

Education Team member of a bootcamp for refugees: responsible for organising the course and monitoring student development.

Codebar coach

Having attended Codebar as a student, I have recently started attending as a coach

EDUCATION

University of Edinburgh

First Class MA (Hons) English Literature and Classics Roy M. Pinkerton Prize in Latin

University of Washington, USA

International exchange Annual Dean's List Meg Greenfield Essay Prize